<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Carl Müller-Crepon</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Carl Müller-Crepon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>At Any Cost: How Ukrainians Think about Self-Defense Against Russia</title>
      <link>/publication/at_any_cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/at_any_cost/</guid>
      <description>In a conjoint experiment, we find Ukrainians to categorically reject political and territorial concessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaping States into Nations: The Effects of Ethnic Geography on State Borders</title>
      <link>/publication/state_shape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/state_shape/</guid>
      <description>We analyze the effect of ethnic geography on the partitioning of Europe into states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Tribes: How Administrative Units Shaped Ethnic Groups in Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/admin_identities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/admin_identities/</guid>
      <description>How did administrative geographies (trans-)form ethnic identities in Africa?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rulers on the Road: Itinerant Rule in the Holy Roman Empire, AD 719–1519</title>
      <link>/publication/itinerant_rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/itinerant_rule/</guid>
      <description>We study the geography of the itineraries of the emperors of the Holy Roman Empire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Reach and Development in Africa since the 1960s: New Data and Analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/state_reach_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/state_reach_development/</guid>
      <description>I show that increases in state reach measured through travel times to administrative capitals foster local development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Ethnic Data from Africa (LEDA)</title>
      <link>/publication/leda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/leda/</guid>
      <description>We interlink 11 ethnic datasets from Africa via the language tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking or Packing Ethnic Groups? The Colonial Design of Administrative Units in Sub-Saharan Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/ethcrackpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ethcrackpack/</guid>
      <description>I study the roots of colonial administrative unit designs in ethnic geography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Right-Peopling&#39; the State: Nationalism, Historical Legacies and Ethnic Cleansing in Europe, 1885-2020</title>
      <link>/publication/ethnic_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ethnic_change/</guid>
      <description>We analyze the violent process of ethnic homogenization of state populations in Europe since 1850.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traditional Institutions in Africa, Past and Present</title>
      <link>/publication/tradinst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tradinst/</guid>
      <description>We investigate in how far today&amp;rsquo;s traditional institutions in Africa mirror their precolonial predecessors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nationalism and the Puzzle of Reversing State Size</title>
      <link>/publication/state_size/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/state_size/</guid>
      <description>We assess the roots of the decline of states&amp;rsquo; size in ethno-nationalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future is History: Restorative Nationalism and Conflict in Post-Napoleonic Europe</title>
      <link>/publication/future_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/future_history/</guid>
      <description>We assess how historical &amp;ldquo;golden ages&amp;rdquo; affect nationalist territorial claims and conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Ethno-Political Polarization and Election Violence in Majoritarian vs. Proportional Systems</title>
      <link>/publication/electoral_violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/electoral_violence/</guid>
      <description>Provides evidence that local ethno-political polarization increases violence before majoritarian but not PR elections in Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Benefits? How Local Ethnic Demography Shapes Political Favoritism in Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/ethnic_favoritism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ethnic_favoritism/</guid>
      <description>We investigate how local ethnic demography affects strategies of favoritism in Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads to Rule, Roads to Rebel: Relational State Capacity and Conflict in Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/roads_rule_rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/roads_rule_rebellion/</guid>
      <description>We find that roads decrease conflict risk in connecting ethnic groups to capitals, but increase it in connecting groups internally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuity or Change? (In)direct Rule in British and French Colonial Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/indirect_rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/indirect_rule/</guid>
      <description>New historical data show that the British ruled more indirectly than the French, in particular in precolonially centralized regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming the Nation: State Building and National Identity Formation in 19th Century Germany</title>
      <link>/publication/german_names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/german_names/</guid>
      <description>We study the effect of German unification on cultural homogenization using genealogical data on first names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indirect Rule, Cash Crop Production, and Development in Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/indirect_rule_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/indirect_rule_dev/</guid>
      <description>Indirect colonial rule through precolonial institutions improved the developmental impact of cash crop agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiefs, Pre-Colonial Centralization and Development in Sub-Saharan Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/chiefs_voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/chiefs_voting/</guid>
      <description>We analyze the interplay of strong traditional institutions, public service provision, and electoral outcomes in 35 African countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads to Extraction: Natural Resources and the Physical Foundations of State Capacity in Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/roads_extraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/roads_extraction/</guid>
      <description>I analyze the effecs of local agricultural and mineral resources on local colonial state building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State building, development and conflict in 20th century Africa</title>
      <link>/publication/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>Spatial analyses of local state building and its effects on development and conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New spatial data on ethnicity: Introducing SIDE</title>
      <link>/publication/side_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/side_data/</guid>
      <description>New data on the ethnic and religious composition of local populations in 47 low- and middle-income countries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>